[Speaker 2] Hello.
[Speaker 2] I'm Jack.
[Speaker 1] Hello. My name is Anne. Nice to meet you.
[Speaker 2] It's a pleasure. So, this is the house.
[Speaker 1] Hmm.
[Speaker 2] It's really beautiful.
[Speaker 1] Oh, yes, it is. But but it's very difficult to keep clean.
[Speaker 2] Sorry. Not a good start.
[Speaker 1] Don't worry.
[Speaker 2] Your accent is very clear. Where are you from?
[Speaker 1] I'm from Oxford.
[Speaker 2] Wow, Oxford. 100% English.
[Speaker 1] Yes. And you are American. Is that right?
[Speaker 2] Yes. But my family is from Italy, Bologna.
[Speaker 1] Oh, Italy is wonderful. My sister is in Italy at the moment.
[Speaker 2] Where?
[Speaker 1] She's in Rome, studying Italian painters. She's really happy. Italians are so friendly. Oh, that's Alice.
[Speaker 3] Hi.
[Speaker 1] She's also part of the family.
[Speaker 2] It's nice to meet you, Alice.
[Speaker 1] So this is Jack, the new flatmate.
[Speaker 3] Yes. And he is from
[Speaker 1] Nice to meet you, Jack.
[Speaker 3] I'm from Sydney, in Australia. And you are a Capricorn.
[Speaker 2] Yes! Amazing! I come from America. I'm from New York.
[Speaker 3] Wow, the big Apple.
[Speaker 2] Yes. Okay. Um, can I put my things in the bedroom?
[Speaker 1] Let me help you.
[Speaker 3] Hey, this is nice.
[Speaker 2] I'm glad you like it. It's a Mexican hat.
[Speaker 3] You look great.
[Speaker 3] And what is this?
[Speaker 2] It's an African mask.
[Speaker 3] Is it magic?
[Speaker 2] Of course. But look at this.
[Speaker 2] A bottle of Italian wine. Do you like wine?
[Speaker 1] Cheers.
[Speaker 3] Cheers.
[Speaker 2] Mm.
[Speaker 3] Mm, this wine is very good.
[Speaker 1] Mm, yes, it's really good.
[Speaker 3] Mm.
[Speaker 1] By the way, you're very lucky. Look, it's raining now.
[Speaker 2] Yes, I am lucky.
[Speaker 1] Oh, that's my photo album there. The pictures of all my friends are in here.
[Speaker 2] Oh, that's interesting, show me.
[Speaker 1] Yes.
[Speaker 1] So, this is Mary. She's from Ireland. Her mother and father are Greek.
[Speaker 2] Her parents are from Greece?
[Speaker 1] Yes, they're Greek.
[Speaker 2] Huh.
[Speaker 1] They're from Athens.
[Speaker 2] Oh, and who's that?
[Speaker 1] Uh, that's Alice.
[Speaker 2] No, that's not Alice.
[Speaker 1] Oh, yes it is after a party. A Halloween party.
[Speaker 2] Oh, that's funny. And, oh, and who are they?
[Speaker 1] Well, uh, that's Sharon and Peter. They live in the flat near here. They're good friends.
[Speaker 2] She's very pretty.
[Speaker 1] Mm.
[Speaker 2] Hello. My name is Jack. I'm the new flatmate. It's nice to meet you.
[Speaker 4] Hello Jack, I'm Peter Nash.
[Speaker 4] And Sharon?
[Speaker 2] Okay, and this is Sharon.
[Speaker 4] It's a pleasure.
[Speaker 2] How are you, Sharon?
[Speaker 4] Fine, thanks.
[Speaker 1] Oh, good, you're friends. But so guys, there's work in the kitchen for everyone.
[Speaker 2] And you are a great cook.
[Speaker 1] Thank you, Jack.
[Speaker 1] Big announcement. Finally, I have all the points, and I can get that marvelous set of Chinese plates.
[Speaker 2] What?
[Speaker 1] Yes, with the cookies. Help me fill in the form, Jack, please.
[Speaker 2] All right. Let me see the questions. What's your name?
[Speaker 1] Are you joking?
[Speaker 2] Okay, okay. A N N E. And what's your family name?
[Speaker 1] Um, my surname?
[Speaker 2] Yes.
[Speaker 1] Right. Uh, Baxter.
[Speaker 2] B A X T E R. And what's your phone number?
[Speaker 1] It's 0454
[Speaker 2] Uh-huh.
[Speaker 1] 786 2097.
[Speaker 2] 04547882097.
[Speaker 1] No, it's 04547862097.
[Speaker 2] Right.
[Speaker 1] You have to remember, this is your telephone number, too.
[Speaker 2] You're right.
[Speaker 2] Are you married?
[Speaker 1] No, I'm single.
[Speaker 2] A pretty girl like you is still single?
[Speaker 1] Stop it, Jack, please.
[Speaker 1] Yes.
[Speaker 1] For the moment, I'm single.
[Speaker 2] Next question, please. Where are you from?
[Speaker 1] Um, there are a lot of questions.
[Speaker 2] It's for your Chinese plates.
[Speaker 1] Okay, for the last time, I'm from England. From Oxford.
[Speaker 2] A X F O R D.
[Speaker 1] No.
[Speaker 1] O X F O R D.
[Speaker 2] Just joking.
[Speaker 1] It's okay.
[Speaker 1] What's next?
[Speaker 2] Just two more questions. The address is?
[Speaker 1] 45 Trinity Lane, Flat C.
[Speaker 2] What's the postcode?
[Speaker 1] EC1 4RN.
[Speaker 2] E C 1 4 R N. And what's your job?
[Speaker 1] I'm an employee in a publishing company.
[Speaker 2] Oh, you're just the right person for me. I have a great love story to write.
[Speaker 1] Oh.
[Speaker 1] Good morning, Alice. How are you?
[Speaker 3] Hi, Anne. Good morning.
[Speaker 3] I'm fine, and you?
[Speaker 1] Fine, thanks.
[Speaker 1] Excuse me, where's my watch?
[Speaker 3] I don't know. Isn't it under the magazines?
[Speaker 1] No, it isn't. Are you sure?
[Speaker 3] Yes, I'm sure. It's not under the magazines, and and I'm late. I have an appointment at 8 o'clock.
[Speaker 3] Maybe it's here on the table.
[Speaker 3] No, the watch isn't here.
[Speaker 3] Behind the apples, next to the pasta.
[Speaker 1] Oh! There it is! Thanks Alice.
[Speaker 3] You're welcome, Anne. Bye.
[Speaker 2] Oh, no. It's late.
[Speaker 2] Alice, what time is it?
[Speaker 3] Just a moment.
[Speaker 3] It's half past 7.
[Speaker 2] Half past 7. My train is at 8 o'clock.
[Speaker 3] Hurry up, Jack, you're late.
[Speaker 2] Okay, okay, where are my keys?
[Speaker 3] They're here on the table.
[Speaker 2] Oh, thanks, Alice. Now, another problem. Where is my sweater?
[Speaker 3] Maybe it's on the chair.
[Speaker 2] No, it isn't. Where is it?
[Speaker 3] Calm down, Jack. You're wearing it.
[Speaker 2] Oh. Thanks, Alice.
[Speaker 2] You're a lifesaver.
[Speaker 3] Hurry up. Go, go, go.
[Speaker 3] Too much stress. I must go back to bed again.
[Speaker 2] Okay, okay, girls, what time is the dinner tonight at the restaurant?
[Speaker 1] Uh, it's at half past eight.
[Speaker 3] Are you sure? I think it's at half past nine.
[Speaker 2] Okay, guys, when is it?
[Speaker 1] I'm certain it's at 8:30. Sorry, it's at 9:30.
[Speaker 2] Okay, okay, it's tonight, right?
[Speaker 3] Yes, it's tonight. But what time is it, by the way?
[Speaker 2] The clock over there, it's at a quarter to 7.
[Speaker 3] So if it's after 6, Sharon's at home.
[Speaker 2] No, she isn't. She's at work.
[Speaker 3] No, usually she comes back home after 6.
[Speaker 1] Hi Sharon. Good evening.
[Speaker 4] Hi guys.
[Speaker 1] Sharon, please help us. What time is the dinner tonight?
[Speaker 4] It's quite late, it's at half past ten.
[Speaker 1] See, Jack, half past ten.
[Speaker 2] Okay, you're right, I'm wrong.
[Speaker 2] Women.
[Speaker 4] Hello, Anne.
[Speaker 1] Oh, it's you, Peter. Look. This is it!
[Speaker 4] Look at what?
[Speaker 1] My office. Here, near my bed.
[Speaker 4] Oh, I see.
[Speaker 4] By the way, where are the office supplies?
[Speaker 1] The computer supplies are in that cupboard over there. The folders, pencils, pens, etc. are here in this cupboard. And I also have two chairs.
[Speaker 4] Oh, good, at least for everyone.
[Speaker 1] No, they are not. Don't touch anything, please.
[Speaker 4] Okay, so you say you have all of the office supplies?
[Speaker 1] No, not really. Um, there isn't a fax machine.
[Speaker 1] There aren't all the programs I need on my computer.
[Speaker 4] And I guess you have an answering machine. Is it useful?
[Speaker 1] I don't need an answering machine. I answer the telephone myself.
[Speaker 4] Okay, you're right. This office is nice.
[Speaker 4] And if you need a fax machine, I have one in my apartment.
[Speaker 1] Oh, thank you.
[Speaker 4] Wait a minute. Something is missing. Where's the coffee machine? All offices have a coffee machine.
[Speaker 1] I'm afraid there isn't one here. There's a staff kitchen on the other side of the house. In the kitchen.
[Speaker 1] We can have some coffee there.
[Speaker 4] Good idea.
[Speaker 1] Do you want milk with your coffee? There's a bottle in the back of the fridge.
[Speaker 4] I prefer it without milk, but with some sugar.
[Speaker 1] Oh, I'm afraid there isn't any sugar.
[Speaker 4] Well, that's okay. Black coffee is good too.
[Speaker 4] Do you have any of those great cookies?
[Speaker 1] Oh, yes.
[Speaker 1] There are some cookies over here.
[Speaker 4] Peter speaking.
[Speaker 4] What?
[Speaker 4] An audition.
[Speaker 4] No, not at all.
[Speaker 4] I'm free. Great.
[Speaker 4] Bye.
[Speaker 4] Well, finally, an audition.
[Speaker 1] Wonderful! When?
[Speaker 4] Next Monday, at the Opera Theater. These cookies are fantastic. Are there any more?
[Speaker 1] There are some more in the box.
[Speaker 4] Thank you. Bye, Ann. Time for music.
[Speaker 1] Hey! Take your dirty napkin away from my kitchen!
[Speaker 1] Mmm!
[Speaker 4] Oh.
[Speaker 1] Yes. I always go shopping on Saturdays. The first thing I do on Saturday is drive to the supermarket.
[Speaker 3] I sometimes go shopping on Saturdays, but usually I sleep late. I'm always so tired on Saturdays.
[Speaker 1] I'm never tired on the weekend. The weekend is a time for fun. I paint, go jogging, go out with some friends.
[Speaker 1] Unfortunately, I sometimes have to study.
[Speaker 3] Oh, I sometimes do a little work at the weekend.
[Speaker 3] When I'm free, I like going swimming, going to exhibitions or to concerts if I have enough money. Oh, and every Sunday, I clean up the entire flat.
[Speaker 3] And in the evening, I watch TV.
[Speaker 4] Oh, I never watch TV. It's boring.
[Speaker 4] Peter and I like going to the cinema at the weekend.
[Speaker 2] Yes, it's important not to watch too much TV. An hour a day or so, that's enough.
[Speaker 1] Come on, guys. You talk like my grandfather. Work, TV, housework on the weekends? Life is more.
[Speaker 2] I want you to take me to places where young people have fun.
[Speaker 1] Great. Get ready, Grandpa.
[Speaker 2] Work is so hard, guys. I wake up at 6:30 every day. Have breakfast and take the train to work. Every day.
[Speaker 1] I know. I get up at 7:00, but I have a friend at work who usually gets up at 6:00.
[Speaker 2] Why? That's too early.
[Speaker 1] It takes him an hour to drive to work.
[Speaker 2] Wow. That's a long drive.
[Speaker 1] Yes. But he lives in the country. I think he's lucky.
[Speaker 1] Every weekend he can go for walks in the woods. Not in traffic jams.
[Speaker 2] I guess that's pretty nice. He lives in the countryside, but works in the city. A pretty nice combination.
[Speaker 1] What about you, Sharon? What time do you wake up?
[Speaker 4] I usually get up at about 9:00. But I live in the city. It's easy to get to work.
[Speaker 2] Yes, but you get home very late. Often 6:30 or 7:00.
[Speaker 4] You know, I sometimes have five or six groups of tourists a day.
[Speaker 2] You work too much, my dear.
[Speaker 4] And you sing too much, Peter.
[Speaker 2] Alice, I bet you don't wake up at 6:00 every day. Tell us something about your typical day at university.
[Speaker 3] Well, I sometimes have classes in the morning, but I usually have classes in the afternoon. On Mondays, I always attend lectures in the morning.
[Speaker 2] And where do you study?
[Speaker 3] I usually study in the library, but I sometimes study at home, too, when I don't have classes in the morning.
[Speaker 2] My friend David also studies at your university. Do you remember him?
[Speaker 3] David Leary?
[Speaker 3] Yes, I occasionally see him in the library and sometimes in the park.
[Speaker 2] In the park? Doing what?
[Speaker 3] He likes studying there. He takes his books, finds a nice park bench and reads there.
[Speaker 2] Not a bad idea. You can study and enjoy nature at the same time.
[Speaker 3] Yes, I like the park, too. Unfortunately, I often need books that are in the library.
[Speaker 2] And what about lunch? Do you usually make sandwiches and take them with you?
[Speaker 3] Oh, no. I hate cooking. I usually have lunch in the cafeteria with friends.
[Speaker 4] Oh, I do just the opposite. I usually cook lunch at home. I seldom have a quick lunch at coffee shops.
[Speaker 2] Okay, guys. Stop with this boring talk. What about fun? Do any of you do anything besides working and studying? It's Friday, remember?
[Speaker 3] You're right, Jack. I'm so happy it's Friday.
[Speaker 2] Me too. It's weekend time.
[Speaker 1] Time for shopping!
[Speaker 2] May I ask you a question, Alice?
[Speaker 3] Sure. Ask any question you like. I'm an open book.
[Speaker 2] Do you have a boyfriend?
[Speaker 3] Well, I go out with some boys, but that's nothing serious. According to my birth chart, I need some Taurians. But that's not easy now that Saturn is in Leo.
[Speaker 2] I see. Anyway, I think you have a strange relationship with boys.
[Speaker 3] Oh, no. I like boys very much. They're great at carrying packages.
[Speaker 2] You're exceptional.
[Speaker 3] Thanks, Jack. But now, stop talking about me. Let's talk about you. What do you think of me?
[Speaker 3] No, really. I'm curious. What do you do at work?
[Speaker 2] Oh, nothing special. Um, you know Speedmaster, the sporting goods factory.
[Speaker 3] Yeah, sure, they produce wonderful running shoes. What department do you work in?
[Speaker 2] I'm a sales manager. Last month they gave me a promotion and now I'm responsible for Southern Europe. That's why I moved here.
[Speaker 3] Wow, that's really interesting. You must be very good at work. What exactly do you do?
[Speaker 2] Oh, basically, I look for new clients and keep them informed about new product lines and take care of their requests.
[Speaker 3] What kind of requests do they have?
[Speaker 2] Oh, they often ask questions about new models and prices.
[Speaker 3] What do you do if they want a discount?
[Speaker 2] Well, basically, I don't get mad. I listen to them and then I tell them, no. Well, seriously speaking, it depends. Each client is different. If they're important, I try to make an agreement with them.
[Speaker 2] Hi, Anne. Hi, Sharon. Where's Peter?
[Speaker 4] Oh, Peter's preparing his audition.
[Speaker 2] Well, tell Peter I wish him good luck.
[Speaker 4] Do you really care?
[Speaker 2] Oh, girls, we're talking about jobs. Tell me about your job, Sharon. What do you do at the moment?
[Speaker 4] Ah, that's an interesting question.
[Speaker 2] Really? Why do you say that?
[Speaker 4] Well, you know I have a degree in archaeology, but now I'm doing something quite different.
[Speaker 2] Do you have a part-time job?
[Speaker 4] No, unfortunately, it's a full-time job. I work for a travel agency.
[Speaker 2] Oh, what do you do?
[Speaker 4] I give tours around the city. I bring tourists to monuments and museums, and other interesting places.
[Speaker 2] Well, that's nice.
[Speaker 2] Could I have you as a tour guide for one day?
[Speaker 4] I'm sorry. I only work with groups. Usually with Japanese people.
[Speaker 2] Oh, well, I'm a black belt in karate.
[Speaker 4] Very funny, but it's not enough.
[Speaker 2] It's too bad.
[Speaker 2] Anne, stop cleaning for a moment. Sit down and tell me about your job.
[Speaker 1] Okay, okay, okay, okay.
[Speaker 1] I work in a publishing company.
[Speaker 2] Oh, so you work with famous writers?
[Speaker 1] Not exactly. Um, I don't work with the writers. I just read their proofs and correct them before printing.
[Speaker 4] Ah, by the way, do you know Paul Taylor? He works with you, right?
[Speaker 1] Yes, yes, but we don't work in the same department. He works in the advertising department.
[Speaker 1] But we are good friends. Every weekend we play tennis together.
[Speaker 2] I play tennis. I'm jealous. Do you play tennis too? Do you want to play with us?
[Speaker 1] Do you play tennis too? Do you want to play with us?
[Speaker 2] Well, just joking. I don't play tennis that well. Only karate.
[Speaker 3] I am beautiful. Don't say I beautiful. I am beautiful. I am in short form, you can say, on or you can say I'm, okay? So I am, I'm. So you can say I'm beautiful. I'm beautiful. Number two, I'm busy. Or you can say, I am busy. Remember, in writing, we cannot use short form like this. Okay? We have to use I am beautiful. When you, when it comes to speaking, you can say, I am beautiful or, I'm beautiful. In speaking, people just want to say quickly, so they usually use short form. I'm. So, I'm beautiful. I'm busy for speaking, but for writing, we use I am beautiful and I am busy. Okay? So remember, I with am. Now, number three. He is crazy. He is crazy. He is, we can say he's. So, you can say he's crazy. He's crazy. He's crazy. Now, number four. You can say in short form, he's handsome. He's handsome. Or he is handsome. Remember, in writing, we have to write, he is crazy. He is handsome. Number seven and number eight. It is sunny. So, as you can see, it go with is. Okay? It is sunny. In short form, we can say, It is it's. So you can say, it's sunny. It's sunny. Number eight, it's great. It's great. You are happy. You are attractive. For writing, for speaking, your. You're happy. You're attractive. Number 13 and number 14. We are sad. So, we go with R too. We are sad. Sad that means unhappy. We are sad. Now, we are in short form, we can say, we're. We're. Number 15 and number 16. They are excited. So, you can see they goes with R. They are. They are excited. Excited just like happy. Uh, they are. They are excited. They are, in short form, you can write, sorry, you can say, there. There. Just like over there. There. So, I can say, they're excited. Right? Number 16. They're hungry. They're hungry. Or I can say, they are hungry. So, in writing, we should write, they are excited. They are hungry. So, remember, not is usually after B and before adjective. Okay? And I, I goes with M. She, he, it, singular noun, we use is. And not is not. Okay? Or isn't. Or for she, he, it, we can use not. For you, we, they, for you, we, they, and the plural nouns, we can use are. And if not, we use are not or aren't. And for you, we, they, you can use the short form like this. Your. You're not. We're not. Or they're not. Am I young? Am I young? Do you think that I'm young? Am I young? Okay. I'm fun. Am I fun? Okay. Am I fun? Or am I interesting? Um, okay. You have to pay attention to my intonation. Okay, here. I am young. Okay. So, the question, Am I young? Am I young? So you raise your voice. Okay? At the end of the question, for yes no question. I am, Am I young? Okay. Am I fun? So, how do you answer? If I ask you, am I young? Am I fun? How do you answer me? If you think so, you would say, yes, you are because I ask you, like, am I young? Am I fun? And you have to answer me, yes, you are. You that means me. Okay? Yes, you are. Or you don't think so, you say, no, you aren't. Okay? Aren't, also say aren't, aren't. Yes, you are. No, you aren't. You are unhappy. When I move into the question, Are you unhappy? Are you unhappy? Remember to raise your voice at the end of the question. Are you unhappy? Are you unhappy? You're sleepy. Are you sleepy? Are you sleepy? Okay. Sleepy that means you want to go to sleep. So, if I ask you, are you unhappy? Are you sleepy? If it is correct, you have to answer, yes, I am. Yes, I am. Or you can link them together. Yes, I, Yes, I am. Or, no, I'm not. No, I'm not. So, hope, rope, telescope, envelope, cope, grope, slope, microscope, lope, elope. Okay. Now, I hope to meet him soon. Hope. Do you like to skip rope? Rope. My father wants to buy a telescope. We have telescope. Could you read the address on the envelope for me? Envelope. We believe that he will be able to cope with the problems. Cope. She was groping her way up to the staircase in the dark. Groping, grope. Can you see that the sun is sloping in the west? Slope. May I borrow your microscope? Microscope. Our dogs were loping along beside my mom. Lope. My cousin has eloped with her boyfriend.